# Marcos Lopez

### Software Engineer/Multimedia Specialist

Washington, DC
marcintosh87@gmail.com
305-803-0671
LinkedIn
Portfolio Site

I am a full-stack software engineer/video producer with 10+ years of working in the health, commercial and education fields in various marketing and internal communication roles. Experienced in Ruby on Rails, JavaScript based programming, React framework, React-Native mobile development and a background in design and video production. Possesses strong skills in teamwork, leadership, project management that can assist any company in achieving positive and forward thinking results.

#### **Professional Experience**

#### Full Stack Developer/Multimedia Specialist

Memorial Healthcare System (2016 - present)

- Web administrator for Human Resources intranet site serving over 13,000 employees and 5 hospitals
- Assisted in developing internal brand strategies for employee engagement across the system

## Lead Broadcasting/Multimedia Instructor/Marketing Developer

Archdiocese of Miami (2014 - 2016)

- Developed an award winning broadcasting program
- Increased student enrollment via multiple marketing campaigns in the community

#### Senior Multimedia Specialist

Florida International University (2010 - 2014)

- Lead in conceptualizing, designing, planning, and producing interactive media materials for FIU Online
- Producing, developing, and editing graphics and camera ready artwork, digital photography, interactive recording and 3D concepts for various formats for marketing

#### **Professional Qualifications**

## Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

Flatiron School (2021)

#### Bachelor's in Fine Arts, Visual Effects and Motion Graphics

Miami International University of Art and Design (2010)

#### Tech Stack

SWE: Ruby, Rails, SQL, Posgres, Javascript, React, React-Native, Firebase, HTML, CSS

Design: Adobe XD, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe

Photoshop

Multimedia: Adobe After Effects, Adobe Premiere,

Final Cut Pro

#### **Technical Projects**

For technical projects please see my <u>portfolio site</u> for different projects and credential access.

I have created various different projects from an Intranet communications mobile application to using an external API to create a cocktail recipe database! Please take a look.